Earth is gone.
地球消失了
Earth never existed!
地球从没存在过！
Halt, Michael!
停下来，迈克尔！
Do you hear me! We will save you!
能听得到吗？我们想要救你！
Do you hear me, Michael?
能听到吗？迈克尔！
Michael! Stop!
迈克尔！停下来！
Pull yourself together, Michael!
振作起来，迈克尔！
I'm going with you.
我和你一起去
- Better not.
最好不要
For the two us, it would be...You'd only hold me back.
这是我俩的事...你只要确保我能回来
It's the only way to save him.
这是救他的唯一办法
And maybe even us.
或许也是救我们的
I'll be back in an hour.
一个小时后我会回来
What is he doing?
他在干嘛？
Michael!
迈克尔！
Michael! Do you hear me? We'll save you!
迈克尔！能听见吗？我们来救你了！
Do you hear me, Michael?
能听见吗，迈克尔！
There's no other signal.
没有其他信号
We will wait then.
那我们就等着吧
We have travelled billions of kilometres.
我们已经航行了数十亿公里
We are almost at the end of our journey.
快到了旅程的终点
Time will pass and children will learn that we were the first
时间总会过去，孩子们会学到我们是
who had set out on a journey
through the Universe to find life
第一批穿越宇宙前往半人马座阿尔法星
on the planets of Alpha Centauri.
寻找生命的人
Geneva. Based on the latest news from
the World Aeronautics and Space Centre
日内瓦，根据世界航空航天中心最新消息
the Ikaria launch maneuvres are running according to schedule.
伊卡利号发射演习正在按计划进行
After 8 years of preparations, Ikaria
ceases to be one of Earth's satellites.
经过8年的准备，伊卡利号不再是地球的卫星
Ikaria XB 1 in fact is a small space town for forty inhabitants.
伊卡利号实际上是一个小型太空城，可容纳40位居民
Alpha Centauri was chosen as the destination of the mission
半人马座阿尔法星，被选作这次任务的目的地
not only for being a star closest to Earth.
不仅仅是因为它是距离地球最近的恒星
The decisive factor was that it is
similar to our Sun and has several
决定性的因素是它与我们的太阳相似
planets orbiting it, where the existence of life is anticipated.
并且有几个行星环绕，预计那里会有生命存在
Throughout its construction Ikaria orbited Earth
遍及它的构造，伊卡利号就像
as a stationary satellite.
一个同步卫星绕着地球运行
What will your father be doing on the Ikaria?
你父亲将在伊卡利号上做什么？
- Nothing.
什么也不做
How come nothing?
怎么什么也不不做？
- Nothing.
什么也不做
When they land on some planet,
当他们在某个星球着陆
he will collect flowers and animals.
他会采集一些花啦动物啦一类的
As we all know, Ikaria will return in 15 years.
众所周知，伊卡利号将在15年后返回
Due to time dilatation, however, its crew, to put it popularly,
由于时间膨胀效应，它的船员，通俗点说
will only be 28 months older.
他们的年龄只会增长28个月
Mars. Our reporter informs us that
Ikaria has crossed Jupiter's orbit.
火星，我们的记者向我们报告，
伊卡利号已经穿过木星轨道
It should leave the solar system today.
今天就会离开太阳系
Master Computer.
主机
End of increased G-force.
增加重力结束
Normal regime.
正常生活规律
Autoregulation off.
自动调节取消
That's that.
就是这样
Get up, girls.
姑娘们，起来了
How are you feeling, Stephie?
感觉怎样，思戴菲
She was frightened.
她受惊了吧
- And you? - Me?
-你呢？-我？
Just don't pretend to be a hero!
被逞英雄了！
Especially not in front of your wife.
尤其是在你妻子面前
The lift off is not easy for anyone.
起飞对任何人都不容易
I thought it would be worse.
我原以为会更糟
Commander MacDonald to the transmission room.
麦克唐纳指挥官请到发射室
If you only knew how many things I wanted to tell you.
你要是知道我有多少话想对你说就好了
I know.
我知道
And I'm just saying a lot of nonsense now.
我现在说的都是废话
What have you got there?
你在那得到了什么？
I picked it up in our garden. A pebble.
是在花园里捡到的，一个鹅卵石
Why...
为什么...
Why are you looking at me like that?
为什么你用那样的眼神看着我？
When you come back...
当你回来的时候
- I know.
我知道
You'll be older than me.
你会比我老
I won't like you.
我不会喜欢你的
- It's not funny.
这不好笑
You'll look the same.
你会跟现在一样美
I'll have a fifteen year old daughter.
我将有一个15岁的女儿
What? Rena! Rena!
什么？瑞纳！瑞纳！
Navigation room! What's the matter?
导航室！怎么了？
We're losing communication with Earth, hurry up.
我们跟地球联系不上了，快！
I was afraid we wouldn't even say goodbye.
恐怕来不及说再见了
This time, there will be two us waiting for you.
此时此刻，我们两个在等你回来
I was so anxious to teach her first steps.
恐怕我不能教她走路了
Now, I will see her for the first time when she's 15.
当她15岁时，我才能第一次见她
You can teach her to dance.
你可以教她跳舞啊
She wouldn't thank me for that.
她并不会因此感谢我的
How are you feeling?
你感觉怎样？
Are you happy that you're finally flying?
终于能飞向太空了，开心吗？
It's a pity you can't fly with us.
遗憾的是你无法跟我们一起
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Never mind. Give my regards to Stephie.
没事，代我向思戴菲问好
Tell her that...
跟她说...
I wish her a bon voyage.
祝她旅途愉快
To Stephie?
是思戴菲？
- Don't forget it.
别忘了
Rena...
瑞纳...
Rena.
He wanted to confuse the computer.
He ordered smoked bananas.
他是不是想想玩坏电脑啊，竟命令它去熏香蕉
Dried beefbroth.
脱水牛肉汤
- And steak with what?
还有牛排加什么？
With honey.
加蜂蜜
- With honey.
And ice cream on garlic.
大蒜冰激凌
- And a steak with honey.
还有牛排蘸蜂蜜
And this came out.
然后这玩意就弄出来了
Enjoy it!
好好享受这美味吧！
This is how our ancestors imagined space food.
这就是古人幻想的太空食物
Romantics.
浪漫啊
Well, I've finished my lunch.
好吧，我已经吃完了
Anthony.
安东尼
Bon appetit.
愿你胃口好
It's June 26, 2163.
今天是2163年6月26日
Morning temperatures around 15 degrees.
早上温度15度
- This is the miracle of the last century.
这玩意是上个世纪的奇迹
A man of metal that not only...
金属人并不是仅仅...
- Wait, don't touch him.
等一下，别碰他
Cloudy, cloudy, cloudy...
多云，多云，多云...
Did you take it with you again?
你又把它带走了吗?
As much as I remember, all crew members may take with them:
就我所记得的，所有船员都可以带上他们
Firstly, as many personal items, as they wish.
首先，如他们所愿，同人类一样多的材料
Secondly...
其次...
- This is a personal item?
这是一个私人的物品?
I have him for eighty years.
我拥有他已经八十年了
It's quite ancient then.
那可真是太古老了
What?
什么？
But what will you do with it here, Anthony?
但在这儿，安东尼，你将怎么处置它呢？
What do you mean? He always flies with me.
你什么意思？他总是伴随着我飞行
But all the robots here are controlled
centrally and are specialised.
但这里所有的机器人都被集中控制并且是专业化的
Why should I care! Patrick is universal. He can do anything.
这关我什么事！帕特里克是全能的，他能干任何事情
But it's good for nothing.
但是它毫无用处
Let's go Patrick.
咱们走，帕特里克
- Let's go.
咱们走
Not there.
不是那儿
- Not there.
Who is she?
她是谁？
- The new officer.
新船员
What new officer? I don't know about any new officer.
什么新船员？我不认识任何新船员
She's flying instead of MacDonald's
wife. A historian. Why?
她是来替麦克唐纳的妻子的，是个历史学家，怎么了？
Never mind.
没事
I don't know.
我不知道
Don't tell me that it's not possible.
别跟我讲不可能
- It is, but on Earth.
可能，不过是在地球上
Come on, Peter. A dandelion or a daisy would do, or...
过来，彼得，蒲公英或是雏菊，或者...
What daisy?
什么雏菊？
He wants me to grow him a flower.
他想让我为他种朵花
For whom?
为谁啊？
- That's not important. - Pardon.
-那不重要。 -抱歉
Peter.
彼得
- I've got only unicells.
我只有单细胞植物
What if you give her a puppy.
如果你给她一只小狗将会怎么样
- What?
什么？
A puppy, one bitch is in pup.
小狗，一条刚出生的小母狗
I would like something...
我想来点...
- Poetic.
诗意
And what did the astrobiologists bring?
太空生物学家们带来了什么?
Nothing but poetry. Peas, lentils, millet, rice.
除了诗歌什么也没带来. 豌豆，扁豆，小米，大米
Acorns, corn, onions.
橡子，玉米，洋葱
- Sunflower seeds.
向日葵种子
A sunflower is a flower too, isn't it?
向日葵也是一种花，不是吗？
I pull, nothing happens!
我伸展，一切正常！
I pull once more, nothing happens.
我再伸展，一切正常
I'm in hell, you see.
我在地狱里，你明白
I look at the casing thermometer.
我看那个套管温度计呢
1,200.
That's big trouble, you see.
真是个大麻烦，你明白
Stop saying you see!
别说“你明白”了！
And do you know what I did?
那么你知道我干了什么吗？
I activated the pulsator. To full power.
我喝了脉动，充满力量
Erik, listen... Twenty kids and a teacher.
艾瑞克，听着...二十个孩子一个老师
I pull one after another! Really quickly,
我一个一个拉他们起来! 非常快，你明白吗?
They're yelling "Mummy"! The teacher too, see?
他们在喊“妈咪”! 老师也喊，你明白?
And what happened next?
然后呢？
That sunflower is ready. Do you still need it?
向日葵已经备好了，你们还要么？
I don't know.
我不知道
- Quite nice.
相当好
Who?
谁？
- The sunflower.
向日葵
Let's hope he won't change his mind.
希望他不会改变主意
When I was his age.
当我像他这么大时
Help him.
帮帮他
Sixty. You have a visitor at the door,
Eve. An important visitor.
60号，在你门口有个客人，伊芙， 一个重要的客人
Me?
我吗？
Watch out!
小心！
- Don't be scared.
别害怕
Some flower we've made you, eh?
我们给你做了一些花 呵呵?
Switch it over to the cabin.
切换到客舱
- I can't. It's a private cabin.
- 不行，那是私人客舱
Isn't this a bit imperfect?
是不是有点不完美呢？
On the contrary.
正相反
You won't get away, Anthony.
你不想离开的，安东尼
I had one after lunch.
午饭后我又吃了一顿
- You did not.
- 你没有
You ran away as usual. Come on.
你像往常一样跑开了，来吧
I had one, ask anyone.
我吃了，问他们
He's telling the truth. He had two.
他说的是事实，他吃了两顿
Yes, two.
是的，两顿
- You don't say!
你别说了
You're all the same. You'll suffer with avitaminosis.
你还是那样，你会得维生素缺乏症的
One has to look after you like a mother.
得有人像母亲一样照顾你
You know I've enjoyed being alone since my childhood.
你知道自从我的童年开始，我就喜欢一个人待着
Brigitte!
布丽奇特!
It seems strange, but I really did.
看上去很奇怪 ，但我的确是那样
I always thought nobody understood me.
我总是认为没有人理解我
Nonsense!
乱讲！
Anthony!
安东尼！
Can you still see Earth?
你还能看到地球吗?
No.
看不到了
- And the Sun?
那太阳呢？
Humans are like the stars.
人就像这星星
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Somebody orbits around someone else for years.
一个人绕着另外一个人成年累月地转啊转
Who's orbiting?
谁在转？
That was a metaphor.
不过是个比喻罢了
- A metaphor?
比喻？
You're here again?
你又来了？
- Does he come here?
他来了？
Everyday. What else should he do?
He's so lonely, no one understands him.
每天他该做点什么？他太孤独了，没人能理解他
That pin head is the Sun?
那个钉子帽一样的东西是太阳吗?
May I?
我可以继续看么？
Go on.
看吧
Nightly she sings on yon pomegranate tree:
它每天晚上在那边石榴树上歌唱
Believe me, love, it was the nightingale.
相信我，亲爱的，那只是夜莺
It was the lark, the herald of the morn,
那是百灵鸟，是黎明的使者
No nightingale:
不是夜莺
Look, love, what envious streaks do lace
the severing clouds in yonder east:
瞧，亲爱的，不作美的晨曦，已经在东天的云朵上镶起了金线
Night's candles are burnt out, and jocund day
夜晚的蜡烛已经熄灭了，
Stands tiptoe on the misty mountain tops.
愉快的白昼蹑足踏上了迷雾的山巅
Where's Herold?
赫罗尔德在哪？
- On duty. November?
在值班，十一月？
Earth.
地球
What day is it on Earth?
地球上今天是几号?
It was the 18th in the morning and Christmas after lunch.
是18日清晨 ，圣诞节午饭后
They must be celebrating the New Year by now.
当时他们一定在庆祝新年
Time really flies.
时间过得真快啊！
It means I am as old as my youngest sister.
这意味着我和我最小的妹妹一样大
Check!
将军！
It's strange anyway.
反正很奇怪
We're flying to Centauri.
我们在飞往半人马座
Why hasn't anyone ever flown to Earth.
为什么没有人曾飞往地球呢？
Our solar system is of little interest.
我们的太阳系没有什么意思
Play.
走啊
Besides, it's too far from the centre of the Galaxy.
此外，离银河系的中心太远了
26,000 light years. Play!
26,000光年，走！
You see, we're the backwoods of the Universe.
你明白，我们是宇宙的边远地区
Michael!
迈克尔
Are you looking at Alpha?
你在看阿尔法星吗？
Yeah.
是的
I come here often.
我经常来这儿
Do you think they're out there?
你认为他们在那儿吗?
At least on one of the planets. What do you think?
至少在众多行星中的一个之上，你认为呢?
I can't believe that there's life somewhere like on Earth.
我不相信在那里会像地球一样有生命
I mean that we will land there, get out from the ship,
我的意思是我们在那着陆，走出宇宙飞船
and they will run to us, waving their hands.
他们挥舞着手朝我们跑过来
Maybe they don't have them.
或许他们没有手
What? Hands?
什么？手吗？
Do you know that Bernard took his piano with him?
你知道吗？伯纳德把他的钢琴带来了
Why?
为什么啊？
He was in some old music club or something like that, you see.
他在某个老歌俱乐部待过或者有点像那个，你明白
Stop saying you see, you see! Don't say it or else...
别说你明白，你明白的，别再说了，再说...
And stop doing this! Who's supposed
to look at it all the time!
不要再做这件事了!谁期望一直看它!
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I don't know what got into me.
我不知道我是怎么了
No harm done.
没有人受到伤害
When one looks at the same faces for so many months...
当一个人这么成年累月地一直看着同样的面孔..
That is why I summoned the Council.
那就是我为什么召集会议的原因
We could not speak about Stephie's pregnancy before.
我们以前不能讲思戴菲怀孕的事
The crew would become agitated. It is a risky experiment.
机员们会变得焦躁不安，它是一个冒险的实验
None the less, it is essential for future missions.
然而，为了将来的使命，它是不可或缺的
I should have been informed as second-in-command.
我本该被告知做副司令
Explain it to me.
给我解释一下
- Stephie...
思戴菲
Stephie has been already pregnant on Earth.
思戴菲在地球上时就已经怀孕了
That means that my wife...
那意味着我妻子...
could have flown as well.
一样可以飞行
If she knew she could...
假如她知道可以...
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不对我讲？
Why?
为什么？
Your wife knew it.
你妻子知道这件事
She was afraid.
她害怕了
It will be the first case in history.
这将是历史上的第一案例
No child has ever been born under such circumstances.
没有小孩曾在这种环境下出生
Stephie is ten years younger.
思戴菲比你妻子年轻十岁
That's why your wife gave up her place.
那就是你妻子放弃她的位置的原因
Lightly.
轻轻地
Not so hard.
不要那么猛烈
Something should happen.
有事可能要发生
It's taking too long.
经过太长时间了
Four months.
4个月
We're not even halfway there.
我们甚至走了还不到一半
Where is everybody?
大家在哪儿?
Isn't Kubes here somewhere?
库贝斯没在这儿的某个地方吗?
- No.
- 没有
Nobody has been here lately.
最近没人来过
Why don't you call him through the communicator?
你为什么不用通讯器呼叫他呢?
This way, I can at least take a short walk.
走这边 ，我还能稍微散散步
You're getting bored, eh?
你正在烦恼，是吧？
It's Hopkins's birthday tomorrow.
明天是霍普金斯的生日
Brigitte!
布里奇特!
What's the matter?
出什么事了?
- I don't know what to do.
- 我不知道要做什么
I hadn't worn a skirt for four months
and now, just look at me!
我已经四个月没穿裙子了，现在看看我吧!
Turn around!
转圈!
Walk.
走两步
What did you expect! It turned out really well.
你还要求什么？真得很好看
Do you think he'll like it?
你觉得他会喜欢吗?
Anthony, let us now drink to Patrick!
安东尼 ，让我们为帕特里克干杯!
So that you know that I didn't really mean it then.
这样你就明白，我那时并非真正地针对它
Patrick, that is...
帕特里克 ，就是说...
- Herold. I am on my guard.
- 赫罗尔德 ，我在站岗.
Shut up!
住嘴！
- Herold is here.
- 赫罗尔德来了
I am on my guard.
我在站岗
- What did you teach that robot?
- 你教那个机器人什么了?
I didn't. He learned it himself.
什么都有没有，他自学的
Will you dance?
跳舞吗？
I don't like dancing.
不喜欢
- Neither do I.
我也是
How are you feeling, Stephie?
你觉得怎样，思戴菲？
Give my regards to Stephie.
代我向思戴菲问好
When you come back, I'll be older than you.
当你回来的时候，我会比你老
You won't like me.
你会不喜欢我的
When you come back.
当你回来的时候
I'm thirsty.
我很渴
Oh no, I'm too old for this, my child.
哦不 ，对于跳舞来说我太老了，我的孩子
Eve will teach you.
伊芙会教你
- I will.
我教你
This jiggling is not for me.
这种吉格舞不适合我
- Jiggling, eh?
吉格舞，嗯？
Nina, we...You're a sociologist, aren't you?
妮娜，我们...你是社会学家，对吗?
We have...
我们有...
- Some work for you.
- 一些工作给你
A moral matter.- I see.
- And a social matter.
一个道德上的问题 - 我明白
- 还是一件社会上的问题
The thing is that she's making fun of us.
这个问题就是她在开我们玩笑
Who?
谁？
- Brigitte.
- 布里奇特
At first, she kept obtruding.
首先，她一直困扰着我们
- Obtruding? - Yes.
- 困扰? - 是的
And now she doesn't want to decide which of us to choose.
而现在她不想决定选择我们中的哪一个
That's really interesting.
- It is, isn't it?
那真有趣
- 是的，对吗?
Oh yes. The reason may be that
she has a husband on Earth.
哦，原因可能是她在地球上有丈夫
This is the Master Computer.
这里是主机
Report to your posts immediately!
立刻去你们的岗位报到!
Section commanders report to your headquarters!
各部门指挥官到你们的指挥部报到!
All officers report to the navigation bridge!
全体船员到驾驶桥楼报到!
An object of the 7th order detected
在第二安全区
in the second safety zone!
发现第7号目标!
Somebody turn that terrible noise off!
谁去关掉那该死的噪音!
Distance?
距离?
309.
Angle 17.
角度 17
It may be a comet.
可能是颗彗星
Or a meteor.
或是流星
It may belong to the Alpha Centauri planetary system.
它可能属于阿尔法人马座类行星系
It's the first object from there.
它是来自那儿的第一个天体
What do you need, Anthony?
你需要什么，安东尼
Time.
时间
Here's your comet.
这是你的彗星
Composition: Iron, titanium, germanium
and traces of common elements.
成分: 铁、钛、锗和微量的普通元素
Volume: 57,900 cubic metres.
体积: 57,900
Weight: 15,844 tons.
重量: 15,844吨
Alright, but...
很好，但是
And this is how it looks from a close-up.
这是从特写中它看起来的样子
It contains organic substances.
它里面含有有机体
- That's unbelievable.
- 令人难以置信
And what about signals?
信号怎样?
- No response so far.
- 至今没有反应
Maybe it's an unmanned station.
它有可能是个无人空间站
No, it's a spacecraft. An automatic
station wouldn't be so large.
不，是宇宙飞船，自动空间站不会这么大
It seems primitive.
像是远古的
Just like Ikaria may seem primitive
to them. We know nothing about them.
就像伊卡利号对于它们来说是远古的是一个道理，我们对它们一无所知
Nothing at all.
什么都没有
- But why are they silent?
- 但它们为什么沉默?
They have to see us.
它们应该看到了我们
I don't know. Maybe they're afraid of us.
我不知道，也许他们害怕我们
Afraid?
害怕？
If they are afraid, then they are similar to humans.
如果他们会害怕，他们就跟人类相似了
We can do more than to send the Pythagorean proposition.
我们能做的不只是发送勾股定理
Prepare the explorer shuttle!
准备好探险者航天飞机!
You can't be serious!
不要那么严肃!
What do we have robots for?
我们要让机器人做什么?
What are they for?
- Wait.
它们做什么?
- 等等
Suppose there are living creatures on that ship.
假定在那艘飞船上有生物
Just suppose...
只是假定...
What would we say if they came to us, opened the door,
如果它们朝我们走过来，我们该说什么，打开门
and out came a dozen machines.
从一堆机器中走出来
How would you deal with them?
你们将怎样应付它们?
Try to understand that there are things robots can't do.
试着去理解那些机器人不能做的事情
Humans will be sent to that ship.
派人到那艘飞船上
Two people.
两个人
Who do you propose?
你提议谁呢?
Stand at attention, Erik.
立正，埃里克
Peter and me are entering into history.
And not only of mankind.
彼得与我正走进历史，不仅是人类的历史
I've been in a similar situation once.
我也曾有过类似的境遇
I understand.
我明白
- I wanted to give you advice.
- 我想给你们建议
You know more than the Master Computer.
你比主机知道得多
I've always thought it didn't exist any more.
我总是觉得它不再存在了
What?
什么?
I don't know, but I envy you.
不知道，不过我羡慕你们
The explorer shuttle is ready.
探险者航天飞机准备就绪
Launch.
发射
Launch complete.
发射完毕
Well?
怎样？
- Everything's alright.
- 一切正常
Activate screen transmission.
激活屏幕传输
We'll keep on trying to establish contact with the spaceship.
我们要继续试着与宇宙飞船保持联络
It's silent. They may have different communication methods.
它寂静无声，或许它们用的是不同的通讯方式
Maybe it's a wreck.
或许是失事船的残骸
Do we have permission to land?
我们得到降落的许可了吗?
Guide the shuttle forlanding.
操纵航天飞机着陆
We are entering the craft. There's vacuum here.
我们正进入航天器，这儿是真空的
Do you see the material?
你看到那东西了吗?
It looks like some sort of aluminium alloy.
看起来像某种铝合金
Prehistoric.
史前的
I thought we would find something worthwhile here.
我想我们会在这儿找到一些有价值的东西
Look.
看
A number. It's from Earth.
数字，是来自地球的
Nonsense, this can couldn't fly out here.
胡说，这个金属容器不可能飞到这儿
Money?
钱?
Those are... Those were humans.
那些是...那些是人类
We found humans, Captain Abayev.
我们发现了人，阿巴耶夫机长
Humans?
人类?
It's an ancient rocket from Earth.
是一只来自地球的古代火箭
From which century?
来自哪个世纪?
I don't know. Maybe the 20th according to their clothes.
不知道，通过他们的衣服来看可能是20世纪的
We found cigarettes, glass, paper.
我们找到了香烟，玻璃制品，纸
The women are wearing jewellery.
女人们戴着首饰
They all died at the same moment.
他们在同一时刻死去
How? How did they die?
怎么? 他们是怎么死的?
I don't know. Everything is intact.
我不知道，每件东西都完好无损
They look as if they had fallen asleep.
他们看起来像是睡着了
Find out who they are and how did they get out here.
查明他们是谁，还有他们是怎么到得这儿
You should have sent an archaeologist instead.
你本该派一个考古学家
Tigger, Tigger Fun.
迪歌，迪歌番
Herold to Ikaria.
赫罗尔德对伊卡利号讲话
Find out what Tigger Fun means, Eve.
查出迪歌番是什么意思，伊芙
Look, Nina.
妮娜，快看
Tor-na-do.
托-纳-多
Nineteen eighty seven.
19  80  7
Complete. We have first data.
完毕，我们有第一手资料
Master Computer.
主机
Tigger Fun, also tiger breath.
迪歌番，也就是老虎气息
Deadly poison with immediate effect.
即刻发作的致命毒药
Does not cause deterioration of objects.
不会引起物体变质
The so-called clean weapon from the end of the 20th century.
是一种来自于20世纪末的纯净武器
Tornado, a type of a military missile.
托纳多，一种军事导弹的型式
No further data available, stop.
没有更多的资料可用了，停止
They wanted to get to another planet.
他们想到另一颗行星上
Overthere. There's light there.
那儿，那儿有灯光
Caution, the ship still has power.
小心，这只飞船上面还有电
- That's not possible.
- 不可能
Why not? A reactor can work a hundred years without operators.
为什么不? 核反应堆在无控制的情况下可以运行100年
A general.
一名将军
He was in command.
他是指挥官
There's two of them.
另外两个
Look he has a back wound.
看，他后背有伤
When they were running low on oxygen,
they killed the crew with Tigger Fun,
当他们处于低氧的状态时，他们就用迪歌番杀死了机员
so that they would survive longer.
以便他们能活得更久些
In the end, they fought one another.
最后他们互相厮打
Vultures.
贪婪的人们
I must be somewhere near the engines. I'll find out.
我一定是在发动机附近的某个地方，我去找一下
What is it Kubes? Answer!
库贝斯，那是什么？请回答!
Herold! Help Kubes, quick!
赫罗尔德! 快去帮帮库贝斯!
- The radioactivity level is increasing.
- 放射线的级别正在增大
What happened, Kubes? Answer!
发生了什么事，库贝斯? 请回答!
At the right, that's from Kubes's camera.
在右边，那是库贝斯摄像机的方向
But that looks like...
但那看起来像...
You always get yourself into trouble.
你总是使自己陷入麻烦之中
My magnetic boot got caught.
我的一只磁力靴被吸住了
Look, overthere!
看，那边
Abandon the ship, quick!
离开那艘飞船，快!
There are nuclear weapons on board!
上面有核武器!
Don't touch anything!
不要碰任何东西!
Come on, hurry!
跟上，快!
Send them the engine module, Svenson.
史文森，送他们到引擎舱
Distance 3,458 kilometres.
距离3,458公里
- The shuttle is ready to lift off.
- 航天飞机正准备起飞
Don't stop! Don't touch anything! Hurry!
别停下! 别碰任何东西! 赶快!
Run!
跑！
We found people, Captain Abayev, we found people.
我找到了人类，阿巴耶夫机长，我找到了人类
We discovered the 20th century.
我发现了20世纪
Would you send them there again?
你会再派他们去那儿吗?
If I knew there weren't any humans there.
假如我知道那儿没有任何人类
Humans...
人类...
They were our ancestors.
他们是我们的祖先
Not them.
他们不是
Definitely not them!
很明显他们不是
You can't choose your ancestors.
你不能选择你的祖先
You know who they were?
你知道他们是谁?
Human trash.
人渣
That left Auschwitz, Oradour
他们遗留下了奥斯威辛集中营，奥拉都尔
and Hiroshima behind them.
还有广岛
The 20th century.
20世纪
Do you know it?
你知道它吗?
Honegger.
霍涅格
Also the 20th century.
也是20世纪
We had to continue in our journey.
我们得继续我们的旅程
Svenson and Michael were to supervise
the installation of a reserve engine.
史文森和米迦勒去指导预备引擎的安装
During such work they have to go out
into space on Ikaria's surface.
在此工作的整个期间，他们得进入太空到伊卡利号的的表面上
They weren't there long, only some ten or fifteen minutes.
他们不能长时间呆在外面，只能大约10或15分钟
Under normal circumstances, this would be an insignificant episode.
在正常环境下，这是一件微不足道的事情
Thus, no one knew that this moment was
the beginning of lethal danger to us.
这种情况下，没有人知道这一刻
对于我们是致命危险的开端
It entered into Ikaria with them.
它与他们进入到伊卡利
How does it look out there, Erik?
从那儿往外，看起来怎样，埃里克?
Alright.
很好
- The robots will do the rest.
- 机器人来做余下的工作
That's Alpha Centauri.
那就是半人马座阿尔法星
There must be at least two planets in the ecosphere.
在生态层里，那儿肯定至少有两颗行星
In the sphere of life.
在生命的领域里
Do you think so?
你这么认为吗?
I know, I calculated it.
我知道，我计算过
Yet, the temperature will be high
on both the planets, like on our Venus.
然而，这两颗行星的温度可能很高
像在我们的金星上面
But life could be there, because...
但那上面不可能存在生命，因为...
I'm not a prophet, I'm a mathematician.
我不是预言家，我是数学家
We will find out in...
我们将在...查明
- In fifty-six days.
- 56天之后
Precisely.
确切地说
Milek...
米尔克...
It's normal.
正常
Will you have a girl or a boy?
你想要个男孩还是女孩?
A boy.
男孩
How will you name him?
你怎么给他取名?
Wait.
等等
Wait...
Do you know which name is really nice?
你知道哪个名字够好?
Michael.
迈克尔
Anthony!
安东尼
Listen.
听
A radio nebula.
无线电星云
Grandpa has caught a nebula again.
外公曾两次撞见过星云
Golly, are we supposed to survey every smudge?
天呀，我们该研究每个污点吗?
Yes. Every single one.
是的，每一个
Alert! Third deck! Lying person! Non-responding person!
警报! 第三甲板! 躺着的人! 无反应的人!
That can't be possible.
不可能的
Alert! Non-responding person!
警报! 无反应的人!
Who is it?
那是谁?
- Dead person! Dead person!
- 死人! 死人!
Michael.
迈克尔
Dead person! Dead person!
死人! 死人!
I...I must have fallen asleep.
我...我一定是睡着了
Well, well.
好啊，好啊
I was on my way from the observatory
and all of a sudden...
我在离开瞭望台的路上，突然...
And that stupid computer thought...
那台愚蠢的计算机认为...
Never mind the computer, I thought so too.
不关计算机的事，我也这么想的
Dead person on board.
飞船上的死人
And it will be surrounded by a large garden.
它会被一个大花园包围
Without paths?
没有小路?
There will be grass everywhere, very high grass.
到处都是绿草，非常高的那种
Report it next time or the computer
will take you as dead with no lunch.
下次要报告，否则计算机该把你当成没吃午饭的死人了
I don't know how it could happen.
我不知道那是如何发生的
I knew one geologist once.
我曾认识一个地质学家
He fell asleep on an asteroid.
他在一棵小行星上睡着了
On asteroid 608.
在608号行星上
Gosh, the whole zone was on alert thinking he went missing.
啊，整个区的人都警觉的认为他走失了
At least 150 ships were looking for him.
至少150艘飞船找他
And I'm not counting unmanned crafts.
我没把无人驾驶的航天器计算在内
I will lie on my back
我想躺下
and look at the clouds.
看那上面的白云
Ants will be crawling on the grass.
蚂蚁在草地上爬行
- And it will start raining.
- 天开始下雨
But we won't run for shelter, will we? We will stay outside.
我们不用跑去避雨，是吗? 我们就在外面待着
Raindrops will be running down our neck.
雨滴顺着我们的脖颈而下
Erik!
埃里克!
I'm telling you I'm alright.
我告诉你们我没事了
I've never needed this all my life.
我一辈子都不要这个
And I'll never need it!
我绝不会用它!
- Very well, go.
- 很好，走吧
It is not a disease.
它不是一种疾病
I'm doing what I can.
我将尽我所能去做
What about biological separation from Earth?
与地球的生物分离怎么样?
That's out of the question nowadays.
时下是不可能的
- And time dilatation?
- 时间流逝变慢效应?
That's an abstract theory, mathematical.
这是个抽象的理论，数学上的
Will it continue?
它将继续吗?
Is it dead?
它死了吗?
- Sleeping.
- 睡觉呢
Stephie, honey, what's wrong with you?
思戴菲，宝贝，你怎么了？
Nothing. Leave me alone.
没事，别管我
- Do they know anything?
- 你知道什么？
And the doctor?
医生？
What if the baby...
如果婴儿...
We did not know what was happening to us.
我不知道我们会遭遇什么
We were not able to cope with it,
我们应付不了
the fatigue, the drowsiness.
疲劳，困倦
We were forced to activate more and more automatons
我们不得不去让越来越多的机器活动起来
to keep Ikaria running normally.
以保持伊卡利号正常运转
It was then when Hopkins revealed
那时，霍普金斯透露
that while focusing the telescope,
就在他调节望远镜的时候
several stars kept disappearing and reappearing.
几颗星星一直忽隐忽现
There was something between them and the Ikaria.
在它们和伊卡利号之间有某些物体
A gigantic body.
一个巨大的天体
A Dark Star, to be more precise.
更确切地说，是一个黑色星球。
We didn't have the slightest idea
of its existence until then.
直到那时，我们才对
它的存在有了一个极小的概念
It came to light that the nature of its radiation...
它的放射性质为人所知
The nature ofits radiation is simply beyond anything we know.
它的放射线性质完全超出了我们的所知范畴
It is certain that its radiation causes
肯定是它的放射线引起的
attenuation of biochemical processes in living organisms.
生物活体的生化过程的衰减
Inducing fatigue and drowsiness.
包括疲劳和困倦
- Where is it?
- 它在哪儿?
How long will the effect last?
这种影响会持续多久?
We don't know that. Or do we?
我们不知道，是吗?
Here are 14,000 metres of reports from
labs, the observatory, astrobiologists.
这是来自实验室 ，天文台
太空生物学者们的14,000公尺报告
Some of them are the first of their
kind and Earth has no idea about them.
它们中一些性质是首次面世，地球对它们一无所知
What now? Will we send them to Earth?
现在怎么样?  我们把它们送到地球?
What for? Why should we worry them for nothing?
为什么?  我们为什么要为它们做无谓的担心呢?
But what if we don't come back?
但如果我们不回来的话会怎样呢?
Nonsense.
胡说
It's hard to believe that a star
could affect the fate of our mission.
难以置信，一颗星星能影响我们任务的命运
But Earth knows nothing about the Dark Star.
但地球对黑色星球一无所知
The next mission would encounter it again.
下一次任务将会重蹈覆辙
It will be better if we do it.
如果我们做了的话，事情就会好些
- Alright.
- 好吧
In the old days, castaways used to throw bottles into the sea.
从前，坐船遇难者常常向海里投放瓶子
We will send a module.
我们将发射一个元件
Yet are we castaways?
我们已经是遇难者了?
Try to understand, if we all fall asleep it will take decades
试着体会一下，假如我们都睡着了，在人们到那儿之前
before people get there, where we are right now.
到达我们现在正处的地方，将会花费几十年
We're not on a holiday cruise!
我们不是在度假旅行!
Each of us knew what he was in for!
我们每人都知道他一定遭遇到什么了!
- Stop yelling.
别吼了
Alert! Second deck! Non-responding person, dead person!
警报! 第二甲板!无反应的人，死人!
I want tough men here. That's all.
我需要强壮的男人到这儿，就这样
You can't blame anyone for this.
你不能因此责怪任何人
I know, but...
我知道，但是...
Those who want, will survive.
那些走的人，将幸免于难
And those who don't...
而那些没走的...
Michael.
迈克尔
When I know that it's a disease,
当我知道它是一种疾病时
that it has a name, I will respect it.
知道它有名字，我重视它
Until then, it doesn't exist for us.
在那之前，对于我们来说，它是不存在的
Is that clear?
明白了吗？
They insisted that nothing new
他们坚持认为，在宇宙中
could be discovered in the Universe.
不会发现任何新事物
They've been proclaiming that for 300 years.
他们那样宣称已经有300年了
Fools.
傻逼们
But it can.
但它能
It can.
它能
Why... Why couldn't it.
为什么...它为什么不能
Anthony!
安东尼!
How long will it take us to get out of this?
脱离它要花费我们多长时间?
Anthony! Do you hear me?
安东尼!  你听到没有?
Sixty hours.
60小时
And then?
然后呢?
I don't know what will happen then.
我不知道接着会发生什么
Will we wake up? Do you believe it?
我们会醒来吗? 你信仰它吗?
I believe it.
我信
- It's not about belief.
这无关信仰
Belief is nothing. Belief is a mere word.
信仰什么也不是，信仰仅仅是一个词
Tell me how to endure.
告诉我怎么去忍耐
Tell me when and how will we wake up.
告诉我我们何时、怎样醒来
What is the probability, what certainty. That's my belief. Understand?
什么是概率，什么是确定性
那才是我的信仰，明白吗?
Prepare for 60 hours of sleep.
准备好60个小时的睡眠
Is that all we know?
那就是我们知道的所有事情?
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿?
To get the Ikaria back.
去把伊卡利号弄回来
You think I'm afraid.
你认为我害怕了
No, I'm not afraid.
不，我不害怕
Honestly.
说实话
I'd just...
我只是...
I'd just love to hear
我只是喜欢听
those words, you know.
那些话，你知道的
That we made up together.
让我们团结起来
Nobody knows them here.
没人知道
Nobody knows that...
没人知道...
I am your twinklet. And your...
我是你的光芒，你的...
No, I really don't have to be brave.
不，我真的不需要变得勇敢
I will only fall asleep.
我只想睡一觉
You will hear me when I wake up.
我醒来时，你会听到我的声音
It may take long before you find us.
你可能要花很长时间才能找到我们
Maybe you won't...
或许你不会...
No, you will hear me.
不，你会听到我的
One day... You will hear me.
总有一天...你会听到我的
I am glad I went on this mission.
能参加这次任务，我很高兴
Only those sweet words.
只有那些甜言蜜语
Those words you made up for me
你为我编造的那些话语
that nobody knew here.
在这儿没人知道
Master Computer. Message for Earth recorded.
主机，为地球记录的信息
I will get her back.
我会让她回来
She will fly alone.
她将去独自飞行
Back to the Sun.
回到太阳上
They will find her.
他们会找到她
I must get her back.
我必须让她回来
MacDonald!
麦克唐纳
You don't have the right.
你没有那个权利
You don't have the right! Do you understand?
你没有那个权利，你明白吗？
This is our last chance.
这是我们最后的机会
I want to save the Ikaria.
我想拯救伊卡利号
But we will wake up.
但是我们会醒来
Believe it.
相信它
We will wake up.
我们会醒来
Master Computer proceeds with the autoregulation process.
主机利用自动调节程序继续运行
End of first shift. Second shift unmanned.
第一次转换结束，第二次无人转换
Attention, third shift must intake the vitamin condensate.
注意，第三次转换，必须摄入维生素浓缩物
Do not take fruit.
不能吃水果
Anthony.
安东尼
End of third shift.
First shift unmanned.
第三次转换结束，第一次无人转换
Master Computer proceeds with the autoregulation process.
主机利用自动调节程序继续运行
Normal regime.
正常的生活规律
Good morning.
早上好
Everything is alright.
一切正常
It isn't.
不正常
We slept only twenty-five hours.
我们仅仅睡了25个小时
Not sixty.
不是60
Eve!
伊芙！
Stephie!
思戴菲！
Stephie.
思戴菲
That's the only explanation.
那是唯一的解释
Some kind of a force field was generated
between the Ikaria and the Dark Star.
伊卡利跟黑色星球之间产生了某种力场
Eat!
吃饭！
A force field that intercepted the radiation.
力场中断了放射线
That's why we woke up earlier.
这就是我们能比较早醒来的原因
- Eat, Anthony.
- 吃饭，安东尼
What?
什么？
- Eat!
- 吃饭！
I think there must be a more simple explanation.
我认为一定，有一种更简单的放射线
Our organism simply got accustomed to it.
我们的机体完全地适应它了
Accustomed? It got accustomed to
radiation in just a few hours, eh?
适应?  仅仅适应了几个小时，嗯?
Perhaps your organism did.
或许你的机体适应了
Mine can't even get used to this mash all the way.
我的机体甚至完全不习惯于这种糊状物
You'll suffer with avitaminosis.
你会得维生素缺乏症的
- Beware, though.
- 还是要当心
Where did the force field that protected us come from?
保护我们的力场是从哪儿来的呢?
Maybe it's just a coincidence, Anthony.
或许只是巧合，安东尼
Coincidence?
巧合？
Coincidence exists among us humans, but not among the stars.
巧合存在于我们人类之中，但不会存在于星球之中
Finish your meal.
把你的饭吃完
The main thing is we got out of it without consequences.
主要的事情就是，我们要避免它没有结果
Just imagine mankind would have sent
Ikaria on this mission without a crew.
就请想象一下，人类将派没有机员的伊卡利执行任务
It would be on her way back.
它在返程的路上
The automatons would have turned it back.
自动装置将使它返回
Fortunately, man is not as perfect as a machine.
幸运的是，人不如机器完美
Therefore, he has nothing left than to hope and believe.
所以，人类除了希望和信念什么也没留下
Blood circulation disorders.
血液循环紊乱
Functional disorders of the higher nervous system.
较高级的神经系统机能紊乱
Will you get him out of it?
你能治好他这些毛病吗？
I don't know. It's not a disease, not in
the earthly sense of the word at least.
我不知道，这不是疾病，至少地球上没有这种说法
It is...
是...
- The second stage?
- 第二阶段?
The effect of the Dark Star's radiation.
黑色星球放射线的影响
- It means we're all in this together.
- 这就意味着我们要同舟共济
No. Erik was exposed to direct
radiation when installing the engine.
不，埃里克安装引擎时，直接暴露在放射线下
And where is Michael? They were both out there.
迈克尔在哪？他俩都不在
Where's Michael?
迈克尔在哪？
- I don't know.
我不知道
Have you seen him?
你见过他吗？
Was Michael here?
迈克尔在这儿吗？
- No. What's the matter?
- 没有，出什么事了?
Have you seen Michael?
你见过迈克尔吗？
Navigation bride, find Michael!
导航控制器，寻找迈克尔!
You aren't afraid, are you?
你们不害怕吧，是不？
It's not that bad.
事情没有那么糟糕
We only fell asleep.
我们只是睡着了
But those two outside, they were fully exposed.
但那两人在外面，他们是完全暴露的
To the radiation of the Dark Star, understand?
暴露在黑色星球的放射线之下，明白吗?
We were protected by Ikaria's shield, we are alright.
我们被伊卡里亚的防护罩所保护，我们没事
We are. But what about him?
我们是没事，但他呢?
Michael is in the corridor on deck zero.
迈克尔在零甲板通道里
What is he doing there?
他在那儿干什么？
- I'll have a look.
我去看看
Michael!
迈克尔
Michael.
What are you doing here?
你在这儿干什么？
Leave me alone.Leave me alone!
别管我，别管我！
Come with us.
跟我们走
- You're sick.
- 你病了
Leave me here.
留我在这儿
I'm dead.
我要死了
We will all die, but I don't want to die!
我们都将死，但我不想死!
I don't want to go with you!
我不想和你们一起去!
No!
不！
Michael!
迈克尔
Deck zero closed. Alert! Alert!
零甲板关闭，阿尔伯特!  阿尔伯特!
Block the access to the explorer shuttles!
堵住探险者航天飞机的通道!
Michael wants to return to Earth.
迈克尔想要回地球
Where is he?
他在哪？
He destroyed his transmitter.
他毁坏了通讯器
Michael, do you hear me!
迈克尔，能听见我吗？
Stop, we want to help you!
站住，我们想要帮你
- He's coming back.
他正在返回
I can't see him now.
我现在看不见他了
He's at the robot station.
他在机器人工作站里
He deactivated the robots.
他破环了机器人
But that means we're done.
那意味着我们玩完了
He doesn't know, what he's doing.
他不知道他在做什么
He can destroy the cooling system.
他可能会破坏制冷系统
Emergency mode.
紧急事件程序
- Or the oxygen regenerators.
- 或者氧气再生器
For all zones!
为了所有的区!
We must get to him.
我们必须找到他
But how?
怎么找？
- I might have a solution.
- 我会有办法的
More to the left.
再往左点
- To the left.
- 往左
Retreat, Patrick!
隐蔽，帕特里克!
- He has a blaster.
- 他有熔固器
Abayev!
阿巴耶夫!
- What is it?
- 这是什么?
I can't see it.
我看不见
- What, Michael?
什么，迈克尔
Earth.
地球
We will be there soon.
我们很快就到那儿
Don't lie!
别撒谎!
Earth is gone.
地球消失了
Earth never existed!
地球从未存在过!
Michael!
迈克尔
Halt, Michael!
站住，迈克尔
Michael!
迈克尔
I'll get to him. - How?
- Through the air shafts.
我去找他 - 怎么找?
- 通过空气通道
Will it work? - It will.
它能工作? - 能
- But... - I constructed them.
- 但是... - I 我制造的它们
Be on guard, he has a blaster.
小心  他手里有个熔固器
- I know.
- 我明白
I'm going with you.
我和你一起去
- Better not.
- 最好别去
It's not for two...You'd only hold me back.
这不只是对于两人的事...你得保证我回来
It's the only way to save him.
那是救他的唯一方法
And maybe even us.
可能甚至是救我们
I'll be back in an hour.
我在一小时后回来
What is he doing?
他在干什么呢?
Michael! Listen to me.
迈克尔，听我说！
Michael!
迈克尔
There's no other signal.
没有其他的信号了
We will wait then.
那我们等吧
We have travelled billions of kilometres.
我们飞行了数亿公里
We are almost at the end of our journey.
我们快到旅程的终点了
Give it to Stephie.
把这个给思戴菲
- What?
什么？
In memory of you?
为了纪念你？
- No, to safe keep it for me.
- 不是，为我妥善保存它
Look what it did to their spacesuits.
看他们的宇宙飞行服怎么了！
And they were outside only ten minutes.
他们在外面仅仅待了10分钟
Burnt by the radiation.
被放射线烧的
Will you save him?
你能救救他吗?
I will.
是的
I will save him.
我会救他
A pebble.
一颗卵石
It's from their garden.
他们花园的
When do you expect the baby?
你什么时候想要孩子的？
He must be there by now.
现在，他一定在那儿了
Michael.
迈克尔
Do you hear me?
你能听见吗？
I came for you. Listen.
我过来找你，听着
You blocked the robot station.
你妨碍了机器人工作站正常运行
You're threatening our lives, the whole ship.
你正威胁着我们的生命，整艘飞船
You're sick, understand?
你病了，明白吗?
You're just sick.
你只是病了
You must come with me, you'll get better.
你必须跟我走，你会好起来的
Are you listening to me? Michael?
你在听我讲话吗？迈克尔？
You do want to return to Earth with us, don't you!
你的确想和我们回地球，是吗？
Earth is gone.
地球消失了
- Earth is there, Michael.
- 地球还在，迈克尔
It's far away, but it's there.
距离我们很遥远，但还在
Why don't you let me go back then!
那你们为什么不让我回去？
I want so see it.
我很想看看它
- So do I, Michael.
我也是，迈克尔
We all do. That's why you have
to let me in the robot station.
我们都是，不过你得让我先进入机器人工作站
That's why you have to get better.
还有你得好起来
- I can't go on any more.
- 我不能再继续下去了
I don't want to go with you.
我不想跟你们走
Give me the explorer shuttle. I'll go back.
把探险者航天飞机给我，我要回去
Tell them, go.
跟他们讲，去啊
I'm not going without you.
我要跟你一起走
Go or I'll...
走，否则我就...
You'd kill a human.
你将杀了一个人
A human.
一个人
No!
不
Come now, let's go.
快，我们走
Do you know you destroyed Hopkins's Patrick?
你知道你毁坏了霍普金斯的帕特里克吗?
Don't forget to apologise to him.
别忘了向他道歉
Will they save him?
他们要救他?
It's that nebula again.
又是那个星云？
How is Stephie?
思戴菲怎样了？
Go to the observatory, you're no help here anyway.
到瞭望台那儿去，你在这儿一点忙也帮不上
I know, but just in case...
我知道，但以防万一...
Is the baby born?
孩子出生了吗？
Well?
嗯？
Not yet.
还没有
Go to the observatory, you're no help here anyway.
到瞭望台那儿去，你在这儿一点忙也帮不上
Anthony.
安东尼
That force field is moving along with the Ikaria, Anthony.
力场与伊卡利号一起移动，安东尼
We're enclosed in it like a ship in a bottle.
我们就像飞船在瓶子里一样被关在里面
And that.
而且
Those radar signals
那些雷达信号
are no nebulae.
没显示星云
What are they then?
那么它们是什么?
I... we don't know.
我...我们不知道
How about Saint Peter, you haven't discovered him yet?
圣彼得怎么样，你还没发现他吗?
That surprises me. Let's have a look at it.
那使我很惊讶，让我们看看它
I would like to introduce our new crew member.
我想介绍一下我们的新机组成员
The assumption that it was a radio nebula,
设想，无线星云的设想
was quite logical.
是合乎逻辑的
Yet fallacious.
仍是错的
In fact,
实际上
it is an energy transmitter.
它是个能量传输者
What transmitter?
什么传输者?
As soon as we entered the sphere of the Dark Star,
当我们进入到黑色星球的领域时
it located us.
它探出了我们
Enclosing us in a force field
用力场把我们围住
that shielded the Ikaria from radiation.
保护伊卡利号远离放射线
But that means... Anthony!
但那意味着...安东尼!
There's life on the White Planet!
在白色行星上有生命!
Do you hear me?
你听见我没有?
Yes. I know.
是的，我明白
- Anthony!
- 安东尼!
That's it.
是那样的
The White Planet.
白色行星
A world of beings that helped us,
当我们遭遇到黑色星球时
when we encountered the Dark Star.
一个外星人的天体帮助了我们
We set out into the Universe to discover life,
我们开始进入宇宙寻找生命时
while life discovered us.
他们发现了我们
Master Computer proceeds
with the flight regulation process.
主机利用自动调节程序继续运行
Entry into orbit from the original trajectory in nine minutes.
9分钟后，从原始轨道进入运行轨道
Attention, entry into orbit in nine minutes.
注意，9分钟后进入运行轨道
Explorer shuttles ready.
探险者航天飞机准备
In an hour, we will be standing on...
一小时后  我们将着陆到...
No, not on earth.
不，不是地球
On...Perhaps on grass.
哦...可能是在草地上
Or...I don't know.
哦...我不知道
In an hour.
一个小时后